Finding Aid for Junior Girls' Play (University of Michigan) publications, 1906-1960
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Junior Girls' Play (University of Michigan) publications 1906-1960
University of Michigan. Junior Girls' Play
0.3 linear feet
06128 Bimu 2
The Junior Girls' Play was an annual play written and performed by women in the junior class at the University of Michigan. The collection includes musical scores, programs, and scripts of the various plays.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The collection was acquired thorugh several sources.
No further additions to the records are expected.
The collection is open without restriction.
The Junior Girls' Play was a popular tradition that played a large role in the social life and customs of women at the University of Michigan. The Junior Girls' Play tradition began in 1904, when the junior class presented a play to graduating senior women class. From 1909 to 1920, the play was also performed at the Michigan Women's Banquet, an annual banquet held for University of Michigan women and alumnae. The first complete musical comedy was performed in 1912 ("In Old Baghdad"). The first public performance (when men were admitted) was performed in 1916. The performances were held in the Whitney Theater from 1919 to 1929 and from 1930 onwards in the Lydia Mendelssohn Theater.
For an in-depth discussion of the individual plays and the history of the Junior Girls' Plays at the University of Michigan see pages 1864-1867 (Junior Girls' Play by Marian Swanson Wissenberg) of The University of Michigan, an encyclopedic survey, edited by Wilfred B. Shaw.
ARRANGEMENT
The Junior Girls' Play collection includes musical scores, programs, and scripts of the various plays produced by the girls of the junior class at the University of Michign. The collection has been organized into the following series: Musical Scores, Programs, and Scripts.
Subjects:
College musicals--University of Michigan.; Women college students--Michigan--Ann Arbor.; University of Michigan--Students--Social life and customs--1901-1910.; University of Michigan--Students--Social life and customs--1911-1920.; University of Michigan--Students--Social life and customs--1921-1930.; University of Michigan--Students--Social life and customs--1931-1940.; University of Michigan--Students--Social life and customs--1941-1950.; University of Michigan--Students--Social life and customs--1951-1960.
Genre Terms:
Programs.; Scores.; Scripts (documents)
- Musical scores
  - Individual songs
    - I Kind o'like Ann Arbor, 1909 (Box 1)
    - I Know a Secret (from The Come-Back ), 1915 (Box 1)
  - Play scores
    - The Yankee Yogi, 1916 (Box 1)
    - Meddling with Mars, 1918 (Box 1)
    - Gold, 1919 (Box 1)
    - Patricia Passes, 1920 (Box 1)
    - Sceptesr and Serenades, 1922 (Box 1)
    - Thank You, Madam, 1924 (Box 1)
    - Castles in Spain, 1925 (Box 1)
    - Becky Behave, 1926 (Box 1)
    - 8 till 8, 1927 (Box 1)
    - For the Love of Pete, 1928 (Box 1)
- Programs
  - 1901-1910 (Box 1)
  - 1911-1920 (Box 1)
  - 1921-1930 (Box 1)
  - 1931-1940 (Box 1)
  - 1941-1950 (Box 1)
  - 1951-1960 (Box 1)
- Scripts
  - The Yankee Yogi, 1916 (Box 1)
Realted Material
Photographs of the Junior Girls' Play can be found in the following collections at the Bentley Historical Library:
Gertrude Celeste Benson scrapbook
Josephine Marie Hayden Satterthwaite scrapbooks
Edith Staebler Kempf papers
University of Michigan. Alumnae Council records